sub2smi by 블랙이글
아이 엠 넘버 포
(I Am Number Four, 2011)
Whoo!
너, 묘기 너무 부리지 마
재수 없어 보여
You know, showboating like that
just makes you look desperate.
Yeah, "Look at me. I can flip my ski."
Pathetic.
'나 제트스키
완전 잘 타'
초딩이냐?
- Yeah.
- Daniel, that was awesome!
다니엘, 너무 멋지더라!
Nicole.
니콜
다니엘, 니콜 갔다
Hey, Daniel, Nicole left, huh?
Should've let me talk to her.
내가 꼬셔볼걸
니콜: 수영할래?
5분 후 선착장으로 와
Whoo-hoo!
여기 너무 좋다
I love it out here.
북두칠성이네
The Big Dipper.
It's my favorite.
내가 좋아하는 별자리야
- Do you know that one?
- No.
- 북두칠성 알아?
- 아니
I got a D in Astronomy.
천문학 D 받았어
너, 누구랑 있는 거
한 번도 못 봤어
So, I never see you with anyone.
여친이 어디
먼 데 살고 있니?
Do you have a girlfriend
out of town or something?
다니엘? 다니엘?
Daniel? Daniel?
이 기분을 미리
느껴보란 뜻이다!
I want you to feel this!
너도 곧 이렇게
될 테니까!
This is what's coming for you.
다니엘, 괜찮아?
Daniel, are you OK?
맙소사
Oh, my God.
쟤 너무 이상해
괴물인가 봐!
He's a freak.
He's some kind of freak.
넘버 쓰리가 죽었어요
Number Three's dead.
괜찮니?
You all right?
- Yeah.
- Anyone else see what happened?
네
본 사람 또 있어?
로욜라 비치 고교
다니엘 존스
이런 거 버리랬잖아
이동할 때 짐만 돼
I told you not to keep this crap.
It just slows us down.
육상 시즌 종료
뉴 멕시코
All right, let's go.
그만 가자
다니엘
Daniel.
태양의 땅 플로리다 주
This is the part
I hate the most, the running.
이게 제일 싫다
도망치는 거...
But it's the only thing
in my life that's real.
내 삶에서
도망치는 거 외엔
다 가짜다
The rest is a lie.
Even Henri.
헨리조차...
다들 내 아빠로 알지만
People think he's my father.
He's not.
사실 그는
He's a warrior from my planet,
assigned to keep me alive.
날 지켜주러
우리 행성에서 온 전사다
내 아버진 기억 안 난다
I don't remember my father.
All he left for me
was some kind of box.
그가 남긴 건
상자 한 개뿐...
Henri says he'll pass it on to me
when the time is right.
때가 되면 준다고
헨리가 약속했다
I got my first scar
when I was nine years old,
9살 때
첫 상처가 생겼다
멕시코 국경 근처에서
near the border of Mexico.
자다가 공격을 당했다
It woke me from my sleep.
It was the first sign that the
Mogadorians had found us here on Earth.
그건 '모가도어 인'이
우릴 찾았다는 첫 신호였다
두 번째 상처는
12살 때 생겼다
The second scar
came when I was 12.
난 콜로라도에서
철자 대회에 참석 중이었다
I was in Colorado,
in the middle of a spelling bee.
느낌이 온 순간
'넘버 투'가 죽었음을 알았다
As soon as I felt it,
I knew Number Two was dead.
Last night, I got my third scar.
어젯밤에 세 번째
상처가 생겼다
나 어릴 때 모가도어 인이
우리 별 로리언을 침공했다
I was just a kid when the Mogadorians
invaded my planet, Lorien.
Nine of us children escaped.
탈출한 애들은
9명이었다
우린 동족을 지킬
능력을 지닌 채 자랐지만
We were gifted, meant to protect
our people when we grew up.
We never got the chance.
Everyone was killed.
능력을 써보기도 전에
동족을 모두 잃었다
남은 건 우리뿐이다
We are the last of our kind.
우리 아홉 중에
셋이 죽었다
Three of us are gone. Dead.
They are hunting us down,
one by one, in order.
모가도어 인은 우릴
순서대로 죽이고 있다
다음 차례는 나다
I know I'm next.
난 넘버 포다
I am Number Four.
All right, well, so...
네, 그래서
이번 학기를
못 채우겠네요
Daniel won't be in school
the rest of the semester.
네, 선생님도요
OK. You, too.
Your new ID.
자, 새 신분증
And this time, you stay out of sight,
huh? No school, no teams, nothing.
이번엔 꼭꼭 숨어
학교도 클럽도 가지 마
John Smith. Very original.
'존 스미스'...
퍽 개성 있네
튀면 안 돼
눈에 안 띄어야지
I don't want to be original.
I want to be invisible.
이번엔 달랐어요
상처만 생긴 게 아니고
This time was different.
I didn't just get a scar.
I, uh... I saw Number Three.
넘버 쓰리를 봤어요
I felt the knife, I felt him die.
I could tell we all did.
그가 죽는 모습을...
모두 봤을거예요
- The others.
- We should get moving.
딴 애들도...
도망가야 돼
벌써 우리 냄샐
맡았을 거야
Mogadorians could've
already picked up our scent.
We're going to Paradise.
I have business to take care of.
파라다이스로 가자
거기 할 일도 있고...
오하이오 파라다이스
압류 중
It's Bernie Kosar.
버니 코사야
풋볼 선수
Played football.
- Yeah, he played for Cleveland.
- Hm. Good to know.
- 클리블랜드 소속이었지
- 유익한 정보네요
- Next time, I get to pick the place.
- Yeah.
다음엔 내가 장소를
고를래요
That's all of it.
I'm going to bed.
이게 다예요
그만 잘게요
잠깐만...
Ooh. Hang on.
I need a new picture.
새 사진이 필요해
인터넷의 사진
다 지워야 돼
We have to wipe out anything
that hits the Internet.
자, '파라다이스'!
Say "Paradise."
Oh, shit.
- 젠장
- 이래서 튀는 짓 말라는 거야
This is why
I need you to be invisible.
Get back inside.
들어가자
John.
존
뭐해
어서 안으로 들어와
Come on. Come back inside.
Little small for a Mogadorian,
don't you think?
모가도어 인 치곤
너무 작네요
I'm sure he belongs to someone.
주인이 있을 거야
He doesn't
have any collar or tags.
목줄도 이름표도 없어요
네 주인이 어디서
널 찾고 있겠구나
Hm. Somebody, somewhere,
must miss you, huh?
Come on.
키워요
우릴 지켜 줄 거예요
Another pair of eyes
and ears watching the house?
내 말벗도 돼주고...
- I'm gonna need somebody to talk to.
- Talk to me.
나랑 말해
알았어, 키워
Yeah, keep the dog.
이름은 뭐라 지을래?
What are you gonna call him?
How about Bernie Kosar?
버니 코사 어때요?
철강 근로자
말콤 스펠먼 행방불명
- 왜 벌써 깼어?
- 생각 바꿨어요
What are you doing up?
I changed my mind.
무슨 생각?
About what?
서로 대화도 통 없고
Look, uh, as much fun
as you are to be around,
너무 답답해요
학교에 갈래요
I can't be a prisoner.
Uh, I have to go to school.
- No. No way, too risky.
- Come on.
안 돼, 너무 위험해
넘버 쓰리는 숨어 있어도
잡혔어요
Number Three was completely
off the grid and the Mogs got him.
- Didn't save him.
- Mm-mm.
소용 없다고요
조용히 지낼게요
Come on.
I'm gonna be safer if I blend in.
눈에 안 띌게요
I promise I'll keep a low profile.
내가 허락한다 해도
Look. Even if I let you, and I'm not,
바로 재입학 할 순 없어
you can't just waltz into school
and start class...
서류 위조는
나도 좀 해요
Do you think you're the only one
who can forge documents?
Hm. Do you have a...?
준비는...
닷새치 식량, 옷
GPS, 현금
Five days of rations,
spare clothes, GPS, cash.
- What's your name?
- John Smith.
- 네 이름은?
- 존 스미스
- Where are you from?
- Toronto.
- 고향은?
- 토론토
얼굴이 탔는데?
You seem kind of tan for Toronto.
Santa Fe, New Mexico.
I know the drill, OK?
그럼 산타페로 하죠
다 알아서 할게요
You keep this on you.
I'll call you every hour.
매 시간 전화하마
안 받으면 사고 난 줄 알 거야
If you don't pick up,
I know something's wrong.
- Come on, every hour?
- That, or you can home school.
- 매 시간이요?
- 그럼 집에서 공부하든가...
And I'll be your teacher.
내가 가르쳐줄게
Fine.
알았어요
바보 짓 하지 마
규칙을 명심해
Hey, John, don't be stupid.
You keep your head down.
튀게 안 굴게요
I know how to blend in.
파라다이스 고교
앉아있어, 학생
금방 시간표 뽑아줄게
OK, doll. Take a seat.
I'll just print up your schedule.
Back in a jiffy.
I know she's
the star photographer,
아무리 사진을 잘 찍어도
형평에 안 맞죠
but it's not fair
to the other students.
비품을 혼자 다 써요
She's using up all the vital supplies.
Emory, come on. "Strangers in
Paradise." At least she's creative.
'파라다이스의 이방인들'
독창적이잖소!
The pictures on her website
are totally inappropriate.
웹의 사진들도
부적절해요
사진 다운받고 싶으면
말씀하세요
Mr. Behrman, if you want to keep
the photos, you should just say so.
Keep the photos?
They're already all over the Internet!
다운?
이미 인터넷에 쫙 깔렸어
허락 없이 이런 걸
올리는 건 인권 침해야
It's a violation to post things like
this without people's permission.
You have to do something about this.
빨리 조치를 취하세요
Mr. Behrman,
excuse us for a few minutes, OK?
버만 선생, 잠깐
비켜주시겠소?
심스 교장실
새라
이건 너답지 않아
Sarah, this is not like you.
Is there something going on?
무슨 일 있니?
- Everything's fine.
- Sarah?
- 없어요
- 새라?
- Honestly.
- Have a seat.
- 진짜예요
- 앉아라
You can't let a few negative students
get you down.
삐딱한 애들 때문에
상처받지 마
Look, I don't want you to isolate
yourself from the rest of the school.
스스로를 소외시키는 건
옳지 않아
- You should enjoy this year.
- OK, I'll try.
- 마지막 학년을 즐겁게 보내야지
- 네, 노력하죠
- 좋아
- 카메라 돌려주실래요?
- Good.
- Can I please have my camera back?
웹엔 올리지 마
교사나 학생들 허락 없인...
No more photos on your website
without teacher and student permission.
OK.
자, 시간표
Here's your schedule.
Homeroom is calculus.
That's B-wing, room seven...
미적분 수업은 홈룸에서 해
B관 7호실
새라
Oh, Sarah! Could you show our friend
to his locker? He's from Santa Fe.
이 학생
라커 위치 좀 알려줄래?
산타페에서 왔대
Job fair starts tomorrow.
Everybody, job fair starts tomorrow.
내일 취업 설명회가
시작됩니다
What kind of camera do you use?
어떤 카메라를 쓰니?
엿들었니?
너 그럼 왕따 돼
Eavesdropping?
That's not gonna win you friends.
- Check it out.
- What?
- 저것 봐
- 뭐?
교장실이 어항처럼
훤히 보이던데, 뭘...
Tell that to the principal
with a fish tank for an office.
It's kind of hard not to hear.
저절로 다 들렸어
Sorry. This whole place
is kind of a fish tank.
미안해, 이 학교는
거대한 어항이지
Well...
Room seven is down the hall,
7호실은 복도 끝이고
네 라커는 저기야
and, uh, that's your locker right there.
행운을 빈다
Good luck... um...
난 존이야
Oh, uh, John...
존 스미스
...Smith.
OK. You don't want to tell me your name.
알았어, 본명을
말해주기 싫구나
That's fine.
괜찮아
That's really my name.
John Smith.
이름이 진짜
존 스미스인 걸 어쩌라고
안녕, 전학 왔니?
What's up, man? You new?
마크 제임스야
Mark James. This is Kevin,
Jackson, Tyler and Max.
여긴 케빈, 잭슨, 타일러, 맥스
존이야
- Hey, man, what's up?
- John.
Good to meet you, John.
Where are you from?
반갑다, 존
어디서 왔어?
- Santa Fe.
- Oh, New Mexico.
- 산타페
- 뉴 멕시코!
Play any ball out there?
거기서 공 좀 만졌냐?
- 풋볼?
- 응
- Football?
- Yeah.
- No.
- Play anything?
- 아니
- 그럼 딴 건?
Baseball? Soccer? Ping-pong?
야구, 축구, 탁구?
아니
Nope.
OK. No, that's cool, man.
That's totally cool.
그래, 괜찮아
대신 응원 열심히 해주면 돼
We could always use more
boosters in the stands, right?
Listen. You need anything,
you ask us, OK?
뭐 필요한 거 있으면
언제든지 말해
- We got you.
- I'll keep that in mind.
- 도와줄게
- 기억해둘게
Good talking to you, big guy.
반가웠다, 친구
이게 누구야?
Look who it is.
조심해
Watch out, man.
- 자, 네 보드
- 미안, 샘
Sorry, Sam.
Loser!
맙소사
저 찌질한 놈!
루저!
Wait up, fool.
고맙다
Thanks.
어디나 똑같아
Gotta love the classics.
학교 짱에게 당하는
쪼다 공부벌레
Homecoming king versus
the science nerd.
매년 더 심해지지
Just get better with time, don't they?
- That guy, Mark, he's...
- Soon to be irrelevant.
- 마크란 애...
- 졸업하면 안 봐도 돼
He's in the third year of
the best four years of his life.
걔 황금기도 곧 끝이지
So, she was like, "The solar system's
sun does not revolve around the Earth."
I said, "Yeah, right."
야, 우주맨!
Hey, Spock!
- 명중!
- 조심해! UFO 날아간다!
- Nailed it!
- Heads up! UFO, brother!
That had to hurt.
아프겠네
Hey, stay down, man.
Just stay down.
He's gonna cry. He's gonna cry.
울려고 하네
엄마 온다!
- Oh, Mommy's coming!
- Oh...
- Right in the face.
- Hey, are you OK?
괜찮아?
- 망할 놈들
- 야, 전학생! 좀 던져줘
- Assholes.
- Yo, new dude! Little help?
Jesus!
맙소사!
괜찮아, 놔!
I'm fine! Get off me.
뭐 하는 거야?
Come on, man!
- 괜찮냐?
- 아니
- You OK?
- No.
That's quite an arm
you got there.
팔 힘 좋네
그러게, 나도 몰랐어
Yeah. Who knew?
UFO 얘긴 뭐야?
So, uh, what's with the UFO thing?
I know it's your first day and all,
오늘은 첫 날이라
모르겠지만
곧 알게 될 거야
but, uh, sooner or later
you'll figure it out.
뭘 말이야?
Figure what out?
나랑 놀면
좋을 거 없다는 거...
I'm definitely not the guy
you want to hang with.
파라다이스의 이방인들
일상 엿보기
새 사진
존 스미스
서버에 사진이 없음
눈에 띄지 마라
Invisible.
You heard me
when I said that, right?
그 말 분명히 들었지?
Yeah. Yeah, because
I remember you being there.
옆에 있었으니 들었겠지
넘버 포는 여기서
죽지 않았어
이 시대의 현실을
냉철히 인정합시다
Let us face,
without panic, the reality of our times.
The fact that atom bombs
핵폭탄이 언젠간
이곳에 떨어질 수도 있습니다
may, some day, be dropped on our cities.
And let us prepare for survival
살아남기 위해선
핵무기를 알아야 됩니다
by understanding the weapon
that threatens us.
Yeah.
How you settling in, bro?
학교생활 할만 해?
- 응, 고마워
- 그래, 다행이네
- Fine, thanks.
- Good. That's good.
I see you and Spock are vibing.
우주맨과 잘 놀던데?
불쌍해서 놀아주냐?
Got a bit of a soft spot
for freaks, do you?
Who's talking?
누가 떠드니?
젠장
Yikes.
너 제법 인정이 많구나
그건 좋은데
Look. It's cute, it really is.
You are an adorable young man.
공 세게 던지는 건
자제해 줘, 거슬려
But I find it irritating,
so keep it on the bleachers, OK?
- 알았어
- 그래
- All right.
- Good. That's good.
그리고 말 나온 김에
충고할게
Also, while I'm here,
I'm gonna let you in on a little tip.
내 규칙에 적응해
영화 재밌게 봐라
Find your place fast.
Catch the rest of this flick, OK?
이런, 땀이 흥건하네
Jesus, dude.
You are soaking wet.
존, 일어나
여길 떠나야 돼
John, get up.
Come on. We gotta go.
John.
- John.
- My hands. What...?
- 존
- 내 손이...
- 헨리, 손이 타들어가요!
- 날 봐
- Henri. My hands burn!
- John...
- Look at me and relax.
- What's happening to me?
- 왜 이러죠?
- 그건 네 레거시야
They called them legacies back home.
너희 아홉 명만이
가진 능력
You, the nine,
you're the only ones who have them.
- 레거시?
- 그래
- Legacies?
- That's right.
네 부모는
로리언 수호단원이었지
Your parents were members
of the Lorien Garde.
You've inherited their abilities. Gifts.
넌 그들의 능력을
물려받았어
능력?
- Gifts?
- That's right.
My hands light up like road flares.
손이 불타는데
능력이라고요?
- And you call that a gift?
- Each legacy has its own function.
레거시마다 기능이 달라
계속 이래요?
There's...
There's more coming?
As you breathe and focus,
you're gonna learn to control them.
심호흡하고 집중하면
통제할 수 있어
- OK. OK.
- Just like you're doing, right now.
지금 하는 것처럼 말이야
OK?
알았지?
How do your hands feel?
손 좀 어때?
- Better.
- Good.
- 괜찮아요
- 좋아
So, what now?
이제 어쩌죠?
이제?
Now?
기다려야지
넌 더 빠르고 강해질 거야
We wait. You're gonna keep
growing stronger and faster.
I need you to be careful.
조심해야 돼
마음을 집중해서
통제력을 키워
Right now, you have to focus
your mind. Get some control.
When you can do that,
you can get back to school.
그게 되면
학교 가도 돼
의심 사선 안 돼
여긴 내 일터야
I don't want to raise suspicion.
I still have business here.
네 능력은 괜한 관심만 불러
In the meantime, your powers
will only draw attention.
You keep yourself in check,
you understand?
잘 통제해야 돼
So I got all these powers,
but I'm not allowed to use them?
능력은 있지만
쓸 순 없다?
그렇지
Exactly.
A little early for Thanksgiving.
추수 감사절 준비를
일찍 하시네요
Paper or plastic?
종이요, 비닐봉지요?
Whoa.
And you wind it here...
여길 감고...
찰리 포토샵
'파라다이스의
이방인들'?
"Strangers in Paradise"?
알아
유치하고 가식적이지?
I know. Arty, pretentious.
Uh... That's not actually
what I was gonna say.
내 말은...
웹사이트 이름으로
적당한 것 같았어
I just needed a name for my website
and it was right there.
이 동네 이름은
'아이러니'가 맞겠어
You know, they should've
called this town "Ironic."
Ironic, Ohio?
Has a ring to it.
오하이오주 아이러니?
제법 어울리네
무슨 일 있어?
오늘 좀 달라 보여
What's up with you?
You look different, or something.
Sarah, come over!
I got a new bike!
언니, 우리 집에
새 자전거 보러와!
OK, I will next week.
알았어
다음 주에 갈게
- Hold this for a second.
- All right.
들고 있어봐
너무 귀여워
Oh, they're so cute.
저기...
농담이 아니고
You know, uh... I mean it.
Uh... Your photographs...
네 사진은...
My parents make me babysit
for film money,
필름 사려고
보모 일 해
쟤들은 내 알바의
희생양이지
and those are two of my victims.
네 사진을...
You know, I'm, uh...
칭찬 좀 해주려는데
그게 잘 되질 않네
I'm actually trying to
pay you a compliment, but, uh...
...it's not going so well.
Oh.
Right. Um...
그래
고마워
Thank you.
렌즈를 통해 보면
세상이 잘 보여
I don't know, I just, um,
see better through this thing.
It's like my own
personal BS detector.
카메라는
내 거짓말탐지기지
뭐해, 안 가?
Come on! Let's go!
Excuse me. Did you forget something?
You had two things to do, you know?
뭐 잊어버린 거 없냐?
두 가지 있잖아
문 잠그고 불 끄기!
- Lock the door and turn off the lights!
- That's Sam's dad?
- 샘 아빠야?
- 의붓아빠
His stepdad.
어째 늘 똑같냐!
Every night
it's the same thing with you!
다 왔어
This is it.
You live here?
여기서 살아?
Yeah, I grew up here.
응, 아기 때부터 쭉...
- It's just a house.
- I know.
- 그냥 평범한 집이야
- 알아
배고프니?
You hungry?
존, 몇 주 전
산타페에서 왔다며?
So, John, just moved
from Santa Fe a few weeks ago.
- The Smiths, right?
- Uh, yes, sir.
- 성은 스미스고?
- 네
- 아버진 작가시라며?
- And your father's a writer?
- Yes, he is.
Everybody really does know everything
in this town.
이 동네는
비밀이란 게 없네
소문은 바이러스 같지
Oh, gossip spreads like Ebola.
Question game!
- 퀴즈 게임 해요!
- 미안, 깜빡했네
Oh! Sorry, my bad.
- All right, everybody, surrender them.
- Here you go.
모두 내놔
전자 기기 다 압수
새라도... 고맙다
All electronic devices.
Come on, Sarah. Thank you.
헨리 부재중 3통
Hand them over.
다 내놔
- 존도...
- 엄마
- And you.
- Mom?
밥 먹고 줄게
He'll get it back after dinner.
You'll get it back after dinner.
밥 먹고 줄게
고마워
뭐? 괜찮다잖아
- Thank you, John. See? It's fine.
- All right.
산타페 참 근사하지?
여긴 심심하겠네
So, Santa Fe's kind of hip, right?
You bored silly here?
Nah, not with the spring carnival
coming up!
왜?
봄 축제 땐 재밌잖아
It's fun, and you and your folks
should definitely come.
맞아, 가족들과
꼭 가서 봐
아버지와 저뿐이에요
Oh, it's just me and my dad.
어머닌?
Where's your mom?
- Uh... My...
- Mom.
엄마
No, it's fine. My dad and mom,
uh, they didn't get married.
괜찮아
결혼 않고 절 낳으셨어요
봄 축제 꼭 구경 가
Uh, you know, check it out.
Carnival.
Sarah will be there
taking pictures for the paper.
새라도 가서
보도 사진 찍을 거야
Cheap labor.
- 난 싸거든
- 실력도 좋아
- That is not why.
- No.
재능 있는 사진작가지
- She's a very talented photographer.
- Question game!
퀴즈 게임!
목소리 낮춰, 시작하자
OK. Keep your voice down,
and we will play.
It's a dinner tradition. Otherwise,
we'd never talk about the good stuff.
가족 간의 대화를 위한
식탁의 전통이야
최악의 충고는?
Worst advice you ever got?
"Pull this."
'당겨봐, 뿡!'
Oh, stop!
또!
아빠, 더럽게!
That's really gross.
OK, um...
"Your parents will never know
you're gone."
'네 부모님은
외박한 거 모를 거야'
It worked with your folks.
That's how she got here.
그게 통했으니 결혼했지
- Stop it. Stop.
- Oh, my God.
여보, 그만해요
새라 차례야
- What?
- OK, Sarah, your turn.
Oh. Mom telling me that self-tanner
looks totally natural.
태닝 로션 바른 게
자연스럽다고 한 엄마 말
She was orange.
- 오렌지 색이었어
- 도로 표지처럼...
Like a traffic cone.
On picture day.
사진 찍는 날...
그 사진 가져와 봐요
Oh, you should go get that picture.
- We still have the picture!
- John, you are gonna...
그걸 왜 보여줘요?
Why would you want
to show him that?
- 보여줘
- 찢어버렸어요
I shouldn't have said it.
I think I tore them up.
미안해
Sorry about that.
- About what?
- My parents.
뭐가?
엄마, 아빠가
They were putting on the
"aren't we cool?" show.
화목한 걸 과시하며
오버한 거...
They seem very proud of you.
널 자랑스러워하시더라
가까운 전문대 가라고
날 설득 중이야
Yeah, and they're already
trying to convince me
to go to the local community college
in Dayton.
집 근처 학교 나와서
They'd love it if I stayed here.
Got into wedding photography.
웨딩 사진이나
찍으란 거지
넌 뭘 하고 싶은데?
What do you want to do?
내 보물 1호야
That's my favorite.
It's got all these light leaks
빛이 노출돼서
사진이 재미있게 나와
so the photos come out so interesting.
와봐, 보여줄게
Here, I'll show you.
봐, 이 사진들...
See that one right there?
나름대로 재밌지?
That's what I was talking about.
What's this?
이건 뭐야?
Um...
That is kind of private, actually.
이건 그냥
내 개인적인 스크랩이야
It's amazing.
멋지다
- 왜?
- 아니...
- What?
- You...
넌 남의 모습을
들여다보고
You're allowed
to look at everyone else...
사진도 찍으면서
딴 사람은 널 보면 안 돼?
...take our pictures, but, uh...
we're not allowed to see you?
됐어, 그만 봐
OK.
That's enough.
어딘가로
달아나고 싶어?
Seems like you want to run away.
I'll just be happy
when I can get out of here.
여길 떠나면
행복할 거 같아
난 늘 떠돌았어
I don't know.
I've been to a lot of places.
'집이 최고다'란
설교는 관둬
You don't have to give me the
"there's no place like home" speech.
그 말 지겨워
I've heard it.
No, no. You can go wherever you want,
see whatever you want to.
어딜 가든 뭘 보든
네 마음이지만
But a place is only as good
as the people you know in it.
중요한 건 곁에
누가 같이 있느냐야
난...
I, uh...
여기가 참 마음에 들어
I think this is a pretty good place.
버니, 저 멍청한 녀석...
Bernie, you dumb dog.
- 네 개야?
- 응, 가야겠다
- Does he belong to you?
- Yeah. I gotta go.
Well, hey. Hold on a sec.
잠깐만, 존
기다려봐
Um...
네 차례야
Your turn.
Thanks.
I'm fine.
별일 없어요
너 어제 수업 때
굉장했다며?
Heard you made quite an impression
in class yesterday.
플래시로 장난친 거야
Flashlight. It was a dumb prank.
But that class...
- 수업이 너무...
- 지루해서?
- Boring as hell? Yeah.
- Yeah.
응
Look, I know it's none of my business,
but you need to stay off the grid.
내 상관할 바 아니지만
새라를 멀리 해
- What do you mean?
- It's all over the school.
무슨 뜻이야?
마크와 그 똘마니들이
널 벼르고 있어
Mark James and his man-tards
have it out for you.
새라는 우리 편 같지만
Sarah may act like one of us...
걔들 편이야
...she's one of them.
마크가 새라를 좋아해?
He's into Sarah?
More than that.
Nobody can go near her.
집착이 심해
접근만 해도 다쳐
They were like the town...
유명한 커플이었...
Whoa!
Loser!
No... OK, come on...
Oh, God.
- Sucks to be you, bro!
- Seriously.
Want a napkin? Get a cleanup crew!
누가 그랬지?
I wonder who did that?
What a loser.
Leave me alone!
날 좀 괴롭히지 마!
Ah, ah, ah...
어젯밤에 즐거웠냐, 존?
Did you have a nice time
last night, John?
You see, in football,
a quarterback needs a few things.
풋볼의 쿼터백은
여러 가질 갖춰야 돼
Speed, strength...
스피드, 힘...
그중 제일 필요한 건
직관이지
Mostly, though, you need intuition.
A feeling when things
are going south.
일이 꼬인 걸
알아채는...
처음에 내 직관을
믿었어야 돼
First time we talked,
I should've listened to mine.
There you go, John.
그래야지
잘 생각했어
Good boy.
Maybe you got some intuition
working for you, too.
너도 제법
직관이 있나 보군
That was awesome.
짜식, 멋져!
분실물 보관소엔
Raided lost and found.
- Nobody loses anything cool.
- You gotta be kidding me.
- 후진 옷뿐이야
- 맙소사
그럼 바비 티 갖다 줘?
Dude, it was that or the Hannah
Montana sweatshirt. You got off easy.
운 좋은 줄 알아
So, uh...
...who's in the picture?
- My dad.
- 누구 사진이야?
- 아빠야
친아빠
The real one.
오하이오 파라다이스의
말콤 스펠먼 실종
아들, UFO에 납치 주장
Where was that taken?
어디서 찍은 거야?
Mexico. The Yucat?.
멕시코의 유카탄 반도
고대 외계인의 흔적을 찾아
매년 갔었지
We used to go every year looking
for evidence of ancient astronauts.
Ancient astronauts?
고대 외계인?
Yeah. UFOs and shit.
응, UFO 같은 거...
Freak show stuff.
다들 미쳤댔지
아빤 자칭
인류학자였지만
He called himself an anthropologist...
He was really just a foreman
at the steel mill.
실은 철강 노동자였어
102년 만에 폐업
He spent all his time preparing
for some kind of alien arrival.
늘 외계인이 올 걸
대비하셨지
I used to think he was a genius.
난 아빨 천재로 믿었어
그럴 수밖에 없었지
Had to, I guess.
Nobody wants to admit
their dad's a freak.
아빨 미쳤다고
생각할 순 없잖아
샘?
Sam...
Sam.
Oh!
파라다이스 철강
말콤, 여긴 왜 왔었나?
Malcolm, what were you up to here?
말레이시아, 런던
아프리카, 플로리다
새라:
이따 축제 때 올 거야?
파라다이스
신나는 봄 대축제
Jimmy, Vince,
come on, slow down, boys!
- 안녕, 새라
- 안녕!
- Hey, Sarah.
- Hey!
네게 접근 말라고
마크가 경고했어
Mark James decided to fire
a warning shot about you.
넌 처음 본 사람에게
모든 걸 털어놓니?
When you first meet somebody,
do you dump all your stuff on them?
네 실수와 비밀까지?
All your mistakes, your secrets?
마크하고 난...
Look, Mark and I, we changed.
피차 변했어
난 사진에 빠졌고
I got into photography,
and he wanted me to be
his own personal cheerleader.
걘 내가 자신만의
치어리더가 되길 원했지
Said I was becoming a total snob.
내가 속물이 됐다더군
헤어진 후에도
날 욕하고 다녔어
And when we broke up,
that's what he told everybody.
완전 싸가지라고...
다들 그걸 믿더군
That I was a total bitch.
And everyone listened.
All my friends.
내 친구들도 다...
Uh... I'm sorry.
안됐다
I'm not. I mean, I was...
괜찮아
그 말이 맞거든
하지만 이젠 되려
...but, um, I don't know,
I kinda look at it like a total gift.
걔들한테서 벗어나게 돼서
Got away from all of that.
다행이다 싶어
So, uh, what's the hottest attraction
at this place?
이 축제에서 제일
재밌는 건 뭐야?
유령의 건초 마차
애도 아니고
이런 걸...
You gotta be kidding me, right?
This...
겁먹지 마
Don't be scared.
유령의 건초마차
Save yourself.
작년엔 쟤
네 토막 났었어
Last year, she was drawn and quartered.
It was awesome.
끝내줬지
My God.
지옥의 문이다
Hell's Gate.
모두 내려
Everybody off.
다음은 네 차례다
Quite a production.
시체가 조잡하네
Hm. Small town.
촌 동네잖아
OK. The last part got to me.
마지막엔 진짜 무서웠어
What is that?
저거 뭐지?
하지 마, 놔, 놔!
Don't! Let him go! Let him go!
Stop it!
안 돼!
Hello?
이봐요!
진짜예요?
괜찮아요?
Was that real? Are you all right?
이거 놔!
그만 하라니까!
Let me go! Stop it!
Leave him alone!
- No!
- Whoa! Calm down.
- 놔!
- 진정해
- Oh, my God. Just get off me!
- Sarah, come here!
새라, 이리 와!
- Idiot! It's you!
- Calm down! Calm down!
- 너였어?
- 진정해
- 이거 놔
- 넌 가봐
- Let go of me.
- You can take off, OK?
- Let go of me! Let go of me!
- Hey, listen. I will. I will!
- 놔
- 진정해
새라!
Sarah!
새라 어디 있어?
Where is she?
야, 뜨거워!
It burns, man!
Dude, let go of me, bro, it hurts!
놔, 아프단 말이야!
She's at Shepherd Falls!
Dude, put me down. What is that?
세퍼드 폭포에 있어!
내려줘, 그거 뭐야?
Where's John?
- 존은 어디 있어?
- 우리 왜 이렇게 됐지?
I don't get what happened to us.
I don't. I really don't.
난 정말 모르겠어
So you have your friend
throw me over his shoulder,
친구 시켜 날 납치해서
숲 속으로 끌고 와?
drag me through the woods
to come here,
when all you had to do is ask me!
Like a normal person!
말로 하면 되잖아!
깡패처럼 이게 무슨 짓이야?
난 좋아서
이러는 줄 아냐?
You don't have to tell me
I'm being an asshole, OK?
나도 너 때문에
괴로워, 새라
But you're a problem for me, Sarah.
Yeah, well, you really
should get over that.
그건 네가
알아서 할 문제지
- 잠깐만, 가지 마!
- 이거 놔!
- Wait. Sarah, wait.
- Just stop it!
괜찮니?
You OK?
I hope you can throw
with your left hand.
왼손으로도
공 던질 수 있지?
No, John, stop! Stop!
안 돼, 존!
그만해!
John. John, stop. Wait.
존, 기다려, 잠깐만!
Hey. I just didn't want you
to break his arm.
팔 부러뜨릴까 봐 그랬어
내 탓이야
참았어야 되는데...
It's not you, it's me.
I shouldn't have lost it like that.
Hey.
바래다줄래?
Will you walk me home?
이 상처, 치료 좀 해
You should really get that looked at.
I will.
할 거야
우리...
I, uh...
얘기 좀 하자
I think we should talk.
알아, 미친 짓이지
I know. It's crazy.
Mark is insane.
마크는 돌았고
And this is our last year.
우린 졸업반이니
석 달 후면
넌 여길 떠나겠지
Who knows where you'll be
in three months?
Exactly.
맞아
Who knows?
떠나겠지
그러니까 우린...
So, I guess I'll just...
언제 또 볼지 몰라
...see you when I see you?
Yeah.
그래
OK.
손이 참 따뜻하다
Your hand's really warm.
늘 네 생각뿐이야
All I think about is you.
나도 네 생각만 해
All I think about is you, too.
너 어디서 왔어?
Where did you come from?
알았어요, 엄마
들어가요!
All right, Mom! I got it!
- 난...
- 들어가야겠다
- I, uh...
- Yeah, I should go.
안녕
Bye.
샘:
숲에서 다 봤어"
얘기 좀 해
우리 집 - 아덴 가 371
John! In here.
존
여기야
So, what are you?
너 정체가 뭐야?
풋볼 선수들을
깃털처럼 내던지고
You threw those football players
around like it was nothing.
게다가 그 손!
그건 인간이 아냐
And the hand thing?
That's not human.
대답해봐
너 뭐냐고?
So I'm asking you, what are you?
Do I need to threaten you?
협박해야 말할래?
폰으로 다 찍었어
All right, 'cause I got
some pictures on my phone,
공개되면 시끄러울걸?
and they're gonna start
some major questions.
- Give me that.
- No.
- 내놔
- 싫어
You know I can hurt you. Hm?
난 널 해칠 수도 있어
Knock yourself out.
마음대로 해라
내 어린 시절은 항상
My entire childhood...
...has been an episode of X- Files.
한 편의 X-파일이었어
너 그런 느낌 알아?
You know what it's like
to feel something...
신앙처럼 강한?
...so strong...
...that every day you have
to keep telling yourself
난 늘 되뇌지
your dad's gonna come back
and take you away from this shithole.
'아빠가 이 시궁창에서
날 구해줄 거다'
And that everything
we believed in was true.
'우리의 믿음은 옳았다'
'우린 미친 게 아니다'
And that we were not crazy.
말해줘
Please.
제발...
Your dad was right.
네 아빠가 옳았어
뭐?
What?
사실이라고
He was right.
About ancient astronauts...
고대의 외계인들...
다른 별의 생명체...
...life on other planets...
그 모두...
...all of it.
역시!
아빤 우릴 버린 게 아냐!
Yes! I knew... I knew he
wouldn't just leave us!
I mean, they found his truck near the
border of Mexico, and he was just gone.
멕시코 접경에서
트럭만 남기고
실종됐거든
- Maybe they took him.
- Sam...
그들이 납치한 거야
네가 온 걸 알면
오실 텐데...
If he knew you were here,
he'd come home.
- 발설하면 안 돼
- 안 할게
- You can't tell anyone.
- No, I-I-I wouldn't.
약속해 줘
아무도 몰라
No, no, no. You gotta promise me.
Nobody knows this.
내 별에서 온 자들이
날 찾고 있어
There are others from where I'm from
looking for me.
I'm not safe.
난 위험한 처지야
샘, 거기 있는 거 알아
빨리 들어오지 못해?
Sam! I know you are in there.
Get your ass in the house, now!
내가 들어가면 가
Wait until I get inside and then go.
샘?
Sam?
I promise.
약속할게
역시!
Yes!
빨리 와
Come on.
요 꼴통 녀석
Hey, you maniac.
- 안녕, 아들!
- 갑자기 말투가 왜...?
- Hello, son.
- Hey, what's with the, uh...?
Hello, Dad.
안녕, 아빠
어젯밤에
애들이 다쳤대
Sheriff James says
some boys got hurt last night.
몇은 입원했고...
Couple of them
spent the night in the hospital.
- You said it was four?
- Yeah, four.
- 넷이랬죠?
- 네
- 다 풋볼 선수고?
- 맞습니다
- On the football team.
- Yeah, that's right.
아무도 말을 안 해요
제 아들 마크도...
Of course, none of them are talking.
That includes my own boy, Mark.
- Your son is Mark?
- Yeah, that's right.
- 아드님이 마크예요?
- 그래
You know, that was his
throwing arm that got hurt.
공 던지는 팔을 다쳤어
He said you were there.
너도 있었다지?
Uh, no. I was actually with a girl.
아뇨
전 걔들 못 봤어요
데이트하느라...
So I wasn't paying any attention.
Um...
Sarah Hart?
새라 하트와...
처음으로 입 열긴
쉽지 않지
Well, no one wants to be the first
one to say what really happened.
But, eventually, someone will.
하지만 언젠간
누군가 말할 거야
I'm sure you're right.
Thank you, Sheriff.
그렇겠죠
감사합니다, 보안관님
뭐 좀 알아내면
연락 드리죠
If we hear anything,
we'll let you know.
- Four of them, huh?
- Yeah.
- 네 명이나?
- 네
힘들었니?
Was it difficult?
쉽던데요
Piece of cake.
Good. Means you're getting it.
좋아, 적응돼가는군
Go upstairs, pack your stuff.
- 올라가서 짐 챙겨
- 어제 일 때문이에요?
Because of last night?
Because I don't like people
showing up asking questions.
사람들이 캐묻는 거 질색이야
이걸 보면 묻겠지
- And I think this is gonna raise a few.
- "They walk among us."
'그들은 우리 중에 있다'
X-파일 추종자들인가요?
What is this? Some more
"truth is out there" freaks?
문젠 그 사진이 너란 거야
Except that's actually you.
누가 널 찍었나 봐
One of the kids must
have caught you on video.
Oh, shit.
He's some kind of freak!
방화벽을 못 뚫어
직접 가서 지워야 돼
I can't get through the firewall.
We have to go there
and take it down ourselves.
놈들이 보면 끝이야
Mogs see this, just a matter of time.
짐 싸, 떠나자
Pack your stuff. We're leaving.
난 안 가요
I'm not going.
방금 뭐랬니?
I'm sorry, what did you say?
안 간다고요
I'm not going.
OK. If you want to pick
the next place, that's fine...
다음 장소를
네가 고르고 싶으면...
난 그자들 관심 없어요!
It's not my fight and it never was!
그 별, 기억도 안 나요
I can't even remember
a world before this one.
그 여자애 때문이냐?
Wait, wait...
...is this because of a girl?
빨리 올라가서 짐 챙겨
Go upstairs and get your stuff.
- You're not my father.
- No, no, no. He's dead.
- 당신은 내 아버지가 아냐
- 그래, 그는 죽었지
He died for you.
In fact, you know what?
널 위해서 죽었어
얼마나 많은 생명이
너흴 위해 희생됐는지 알아?
You have no idea how many others
have made sacrifices so you could live!
헌데 넌
사랑 타령이야?
And it wasn't so you could come here
마치 진짜 사람인 양?
and experience puppy love
like a real live boy!
I'm not leaving.
난 안 가요
John... John!
존?
존!
난 안 가요!
I'm not leaving!
Oh, yeah, I can do that now.
봤죠?
이젠 이런 것도 해요
존!
Hey, John!
놔주마, 알았지?
I'm letting go, OK?
- OK?
- OK.
- 알았냐고?
- 네
우리 별엔...
- On our planet...
- Just tell me why they want to kill me.
왜 날 쫓는지나 말해요
The Mogs, they don't colonize.
They decimate. And then they move on.
모가도어 인은 타 종족을
학살하고 영토를 확장해왔어
다음은 지구 차례야
And now, they've moved here.
There are few forces that can stop them.
You and the other five can.
그들을 막을 수 있는 건
너와 다른 다섯뿐이야
너흰 큰 사명이 있어
You were saved for a bigger purpose.
I'm not gonna let you throw that away
for a girl.
여자애 때문에
그걸 망칠 순 없어
She's not just a girl.
걘 딴 애와 달라요
I think about leaving her...
걜 떠날 생각도 했지만
그럴 수가 없어요
...but I can't.
And I don't know why.
왠지 모르겠어요
우린 인간과 달라
우리 사랑은 영원해
We don't love like the humans.
With us, it's forever.
절대 잊지 못하지
You never forget.
걔가 네게 그런 존재면
놈들에게 지지마
If she is that for you,
then don't let them win.
Or you'll never forgive yourself.
지면 너 자신을
용서 못 할 테니까...
Now, we have to go.
이제 가야 돼
I'll take care of the website tonight.
Buy you a day.
웹은 내게 맡겨
하루 주마
하루 동안에
작별하라고요?
A day? To say goodbye?
우리 땐 그런 배려도 없었어
That's more than the rest of us had.
그들은 우리 중에 있다
He's some kind of freak!
Henri, I'm going to Sarah's.
헨리, 새라 만나러 가요
헨리?
Henri?
헨리? 여보세요?
헨리?
Henri? Hello? Henri?
아냐, 이리 와
만나게 해 줄 테니까...
No, but come here
and I'll tell you how to find him.
당신 누구야?
헨리는?
Who are you? Where's Henri?
월소우 윌라드 코트
417번지
417 Willard Court,
Warsaw, Indiana.
Come on, come on.
빨리 받아
I need your help.
네 도움이 필요해
너흰 그런 짓 안 해?
So, you guys... you guys don't...
- 납치?
- 응
- Abduct people?
- Yeah.
안 해
No.
But the other guys,
the ones that are chasing you...
널 쫓는 다른 종족은...
납치해?
...they do?
새라
여기야
That's it.
고맙다
Thanks.
Whoa! You brought a gun?
뭐야, 총도 가져왔어?
의붓아빠 거야
필요할 거야, 가자
I stole it from Ed.
It might come in handy. Let's go.
- 안 돼
- 난 널 도와주러 왔어
- No.
- Dude, I came here to help you.
이미 도와줬어
이제 집에 가
You have. Now, go home.
우리- 중에-
있다- 닷컴
Whoa!
- 뭐야?
- 난 안 가
- What are you doing?
- I'm not bailing.
놈들이 아빨 데려갔으면?
What if these Mog people took my dad?
Holy shit!
맙소사!
완전히 잠가 버렸네
But you just dead-bolted it.
작전을 바꾸자
- OK. New plan.
- Yeah.
넌 쟬 감시해
오면 문자 쳐
You follow that guy and you
text me if he comes back, OK?
Copy that. I'm on it.
알았어, 염려 마
농부 실종
훼손된 소 사체 발견
납치된 소녀 찾기 운동
Henri.
헨리
- 괜찮아요?
- 여길 왜 와?
- Are you OK?
- You're not supposed to be here.
- 무슨 일이에요?
- 놈들의 함정이야
- What happened?
- The Mogs set this up.
We need to leave. They're coming.
가야 돼
놈들이 와
Everybody stays right where they are
or I'll shoot this kid.
누구든 움직이면
얠 쏘겠다
I'll do it!
Get your hands up!
농담 아냐!
손 올려!
So glad you brought the gun.
총 잘 가져왔네
You're Malcolm's boy.
말콤의 아들이군
- Get the lights, will you?
- Shut up! Get your hands up!
- 불 좀 끌래?
- 닥쳐! 손 올리래도!
Oh!
너 우리 사이트에 뜬
동영상의 걔지?
You! You're the one
from the video on our site.
- 그들이 쫓는...
- 그들이라니?
- The one they're after.
- The one who's after?
- What's he talking about?
- The Mogs, they've been here.
- 무슨 소리죠?
- 모가도어 인이 왔었어
- This was a trap.
- Yeah.
함정이었어
그자들 누군진 몰라도
계획이 굉장하던데?
These dudes, whatever they are, man,
they got plans, know what I'm sayin'?
- John...
- I'm that guy, the conspiracy guy.
다들 내 말을 안 믿고
개 무시 했지만
Nobody gives a crap what I say.
But this is real, man!
이건 진짜야!
John. It's time to leave.
존, 가야 돼
그들은 여기가 맘에 든대
They like it here, Earth. They're gonna
take all this shit, everything!
모든 걸 뺏을 거래!
존, 어서!
John! Now!
We either do what they say
or we are all gonna die.
시키는 대로 안 하면
다 죽어
It's time to go! Now!
지금 가야 돼!
존, 존, 안 돼!
John. John! John, no!
존, 가!
John, go!
- Now!
- Go!
- 어서!
- 가자!
시동 걸어
출발해!
Start the car.
Come on! Get us out of here!
- I can't find the keys!
- What do you mean?
- 키가 없어!
- 키가 없다니?
- 키를 못 찾겠어!
- 빨리!
- I can't find the keys!
- Come on! Come on!
Guys, what are we waiting for?
뭘 기다려?
- I've lost the keys!
- John, start the engine.
- 키가 없어요!
- 존, 시동 걸어
- What?
- You can do it. Start the car.
넌 할 수 있어
시동 걸어!
- Come on.
- Start the car.
- 제발...
- 빨리 걸어
Whoa, whoa. Come on, come on!
He's coming! He's coming!
빨리해, 온다!
온다고, 시동 걸어!
네 힘을 써!
Start the car! Start the car!
Use your magic powers!
Come on! We are so dead!
잡히면 다 죽어!
Oh, my God!
맙소사!
Go! Drive the car!
출발해, 어서 가!
You take this.
이거 받아
Malcolm was using it
to track the others.
말콤은 이걸로
딴 애들을 찾았어
- Wait. So, my dad was...
- He was helping us.
그럼 우리 아빠가...
우릴 도왔지
다 모이게 하려고...
He was supposed to bring us together.
네가 나머질 찾아
You need to find the others.
모이면 더 강해져
Together you'll be more powerful.
당신 없인 못 해요
I can't do this without you.
할 수 있어
Yes, you can.
넌 할 수 있어
You have no idea
what you're capable of.
넌 네 능력을
아직 다 몰라
헨리
Henri.
Just let me talk.
내가 얘기할게
당신이 시키는 대로
전화했어요
OK. So, I called you like you said.
I mean, it's not my fault they got...
놓친 건 내 탓이...
우린
우리 몫을 했어요
I mean, we held up our end.
- Hm.
- We're still in?
끼워줄 거죠?
새로운 세상의
지배자로?
The whole new world order thing?
The Locator.
위치 추적기
어디 있나?
- Where is it?
- OK.
All he had was a knife and that rock.
그는 칼만 갖고 있었어요
그 돌멩이랑...
And I put it...
내가 그 돌을...
저기 뒀는데...
- It was over there, man.
- "It was over there, man."
하지만 지금은 없잖아
But it's not there now.
냄새가 납니다
넘버 포가 근처에 있군
만화는 애들이 보는 거야
Cartoons for children.
Where I'm from, men have to work.
우리 별에선
남잔 일만 해
Look, I'll work hard.
열심히 일할게요
현실 도피적인 인간의
나태한 모습...
The disregard that so many of you
have for practical matters,
정말 아름답군!
it's... beautiful.
재밌는 놀이 좀 할까?
I think we should
all have some fun. Huh?
Gadgets.
You call them "toys for boys."
남잔 신기한 기계를 좋아하지
I have a gadget.
나도 멋진 거 있어
갖고 놀게 해줄까?
- Would you like to play with it?
- Uh... No, no. I...
아뇨, 됐어요
It wants to play with you!
얜 너랑 놀고 싶대!
Need to talk to you.
얘기 좀 하자
Any idea where
I might find your friend?
네 친구 어디 있는지 아니?
He's not who you think he is.
넌 걔 정체를 몰라
Excuse me?
뭐라고요?
The Paradise Sheriff's Department
파라다이스 보안관은
두 용의자의 집을 급습
raided the home of two suspects,
seizing computers
and several suspicious items.
컴퓨터 등을 압수하고
An APB has been issued on
the suspects and anyone with...
둘을 긴급 수배했습니다
둘의 소재를...
여길 떠야 돼
We need to get out of here.
너와 헨리가
There's a news thing.
범죄자나 테러리스트로
의심받고 있어
The cops think you and Henri
are criminals or terrorists.
새라:
너 누구야?
돌아가자
We're going back.
I'm outside of
the home here in Warsaw
그들의 집 밖에서
where the mutilated bodies of
two paranormal website operators
웹 운영자 둘의
훼손된 시신이
발견됐습니다
were just found a few hours ago.
The police are not saying
if they have any leads
경찰은 사건의 동기나
or even why these
brutal murders occurred.
단서에 대해 함구 중입니다
아직 용의자는 없지만
Police have no suspects
at this time...
현재 활발한 수사가
이뤄지고 있습니다
나도 그거 있어
- I have one of those!
- What?
One of those.
I took it from my dad's stash.
그거!
아빠 아지트에 있었어
가서 가져와
- I need you to get it.
- Yeah, yeah.
린데일에서 내려줘
새라네 집이 거기야
Let me off at Linndale.
Sarah's at a house up there.
- 이따 전화할게
- 그리고?
I'll call you after.
- And then what?
- Then I get the rock and you go home.
넌 돌 주고 가
- It's him.
- John?
- Did you see that?
- What's he doing here?
Yeah, he's here.
네, 왔어요
That's him!
제발...
Come on.
넌 쟤들과 안 어울려
Doesn't seem like your kind of crowd.
Not so sure who my
kind of crowd is right now.
이젠 내가 누구와
어울리는지 모르겠어
- Look, just...
- John Smith?
- 새라...
- 존 스미스?
I'm such an idiot.
난 정말 바보야
다들 네 아빠가
테러리스트래
And they're saying that your dad
is some kind of terrorist.
그런 거 아냐
He's not a terrorist.
Tell me the truth.
진실을 말해줘
Who are you?
넌 누구지?
He's upstairs.
2층에 있어요
저리들 비켜
All right, guys, out of the way.
묻잖아, 대답해 봐
You didn't answer my question.
I just came to say goodbye.
작별 인사하러 왔어
- John, wait! What are you... No, John!
- Don't move!
- 존, 잠깐!
- 꼼짝 마!
- 안 돼, 존!
- 새라!
Sarah!
어떻게...
How...
- Move! Move!
- Go!
빨리 잡아!
That was awesome!
Whoa...
방금 그거, 불가능해
What you did is not possible.
Who I am...
내가 누군지
...it's all in here.
I took these for you.
여기 다 있어
보라고 가져왔어
잠깐만, 나랑 같이 가
부탁이야
Wait. Come with me.
Please.
어디로 갔는지 아니?
Any idea where they'd be?
대충 알 거 같아요
I think I know
where she might go.
- Who the hell are they?
- Big-ass linebackers?
- 저 사람들 누구지?
- 풋볼 선수들인가?
맙소사
Holy shit...
안 돼, 안 돼!
No, no, no!
아빠!
Dad!
얠 족치면 넘버 포를
찾을 수 있어
An alcohol-fuelled
young guy like you...
어린 녀석이
술을 많이 먹는군
...healthy and well-fed.
건강하고 몸집도 좋고...
I bet you watch a lot of television,
don't you? Do you? Do you?
TV도 많이 보겠군
맞지? 맞지?
- Yeah.
- 네
- 네?
In this situation here,
you're probably thinking,
지금 넌
이렇게 생각할 거야
'내가 오늘
영웅 노릇 좀 해볼까?'
"Maybe I could save the day.
Maybe I could be the hero."
경고하는데
그런 짓 마
But I say... don't do that.
OK?
알겠냐?
말해 봐
그 녀석 어디 있지?
Tell me now, where is the boy?
These are beautiful.
참 아름답다
그거 보여줄래?
Can you show me?
안 돼, 안 돼!
- No!
- Get in!
Let me go! Let me go!
이거 놔, 놓으란 말이야!
학교를 포위하고
전원을 차단해
Let go of me!
이거 놔!
- 여보세요
- 어디야?
- Hello?
- Where are you?
I'm at the high school.
학교에 있어
Yeah, you need to get out of there now.
당장 거기서 나와
무슨 일인데?
Why? What's happening?
Your stunt with the car
is already on YouTube.
네 자동차 묘기
유튜브에 떴어
놈들이 곧
들이닥칠 거야
If they're not right on your ass now,
they will be soon.
가자
Come on.
And don't tell me this is not my fight.
난 빠지라는 말
하지 마
아빤 저들이 올 걸 알았어
그래서 끌려간 거야
My dad probably knew those guys were
coming and that's why they took him.
And also, I have your dog.
참, 네 개도 데려왔어
Look, I'm on my way.
지금 갈게
I'll meet you out front of the school.
학교 앞에서 만나
당장 피해야 돼!
You've got to get out now.
John?
존?
John!
존!
Let's go.
가자
Let go of me!
이거 놔!
맙소사!
Jesus!
Sarah! If you're in there, run!
새라, 그 안에 있으면
달아나!
Run!
Let me go!
이거 놔!
잘 들어
내가 널 지켜줄 거야
Listen to me. I'm not gonna
let them hurt you, OK?
알았지?
가자
Do you understand me?
Come on.
인터넷에
'나 여기 있소' 광고하냐?
Lt'd be a good idea, cowboy, if you
kept your heroics off the Internet.
넌 누구지?
- Who are you?
- Number Six. Where's your protector?
넘버 식스
네 수호자는?
- Dead.
- Yeah. Mine, too.
죽었어
내 수호자도
넉 달 전에 당했어
Mogs got her four months ago.
- We've been tracking them down.
- Tracking them?
- 우린 놈들을 추적해왔지
- 추적?
응
그 덕에 네가 산 거야
Yeah. Lucky for you, I saved your ass.
너 자신이나 잘 지켜
You should be watching your own ass.
Mogs have all the exits covered.
출구는 다 차단됐어
Looks like you're gonna
have to fight to get out.
놈들과 싸워서
길을 뚫어야 돼
- Are you game?
- Yeah.
- 준비됐어?
- 응
There's a tunnel under the school
that leads to the stadium.
스타디움으로 향하는
지하 터널이 있어
Oh, you made friends.
How nice.
친구를 사귀었군
멋지네
Let's go.
가자
너 다른 레거시도 있니?
Got any other legacies
I should know about?
곧 보게 돼
Stay tuned.
Oh, shit.
맙소사
Oh, shit!
맙소사!
Careful, they'll see us.
조심해, 보일라
에너지를 아껴둬야 돼
And you're going
to need all your energy.
- 무슨 소리지?
- 놈들이겠지
- What was that?
- They're comin'.
Ah! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Whoa! Sam, what are you doing?
샘, 여기서 뭐해?
차에서 나온 괴물 봤어?
Did you see what just
flew out of that truck?
네 개가 괴물로 변해서
And your dog just shape-shifted
into one of them.
날 잡아먹을 뻔 했어
자, 네 돌!
I thought he was gonna eat me.
Here's your rock.
안녕, 난 샘이야
네 이름은?
Hi! I'm Sam. What's your name?
Jane Doe.
제인 도우
이름 좋네
That's cool. It's cool.
너도 번호 있냐?
So, are you a number, too?
- Who is this tool?
- Sam, focus.
- 쟤 뭐야?
- 샘, 딴 짓 말고!
차에서 뭐가 나왔다고?
What flew out of the truck?
Come on! Go, go!
도망가, 어서!
Sam. Come on! Go!
샘, 빨리 가!
덤벼, 덤벼!
Come on! Come on!
덤벼!
Come on!
Ahh!
- Hit me.
- What?
- 쏴 줘
- 뭐?
네 빛으로
내 파워를 높여줘
With your lumen.
I need to power-up.
Hit me!
쏴!
Red Bull's for pussies.
레드불은 쨉도 안 되지
He killed Henri. I want him.
헨리의 원수야
내가 처리할게
Ah!
Four!
넘버 포!
손을 잘 쓰네
You're good with your hands.
- 고맙다
- 천만에...
- Thanks.
- No problem.
- 내 개가...
- 걘 키메라야
- My dog, he, uh... he just...
- Yeah, he's a chimera.
로리언에서 널 따라왔지
He came with you from Lorien.
널 지켜주려고...
Someone had to look after you.
총은 왜?
게임하냐?
You brought a gun?
Are you serious?
- What? It might come in handy.
- This way.
- 필요할 거야
- 이쪽이야
Go!
가자!
- Take her back to the tunnel!
- Got it! Come on!
- 터널로 데려가!
- 가자
젠장!
- Holy...!
- Ahh!
게임을 많이 해서...
I play a lot of Xbox.
Oh!
Oh! Ahh!
넘버 포, 네가 가진 걸
내게 줘야겠다
Number Four, I think you
have something I need. Hm?
고맙다, 일을 쉽게
끝내게 해줘서...
Oh, thank you for making
this so nice and easy.
Think of how quickly we'll finish off
the rest of the planet. It's fantastic!
이제 순식간에
이 별은 끝장나
멋지지?
Soon, I'll be done with all of you.
이제 너흴
다 죽여주마
Just relax.
긴장 풀어
어차피 넌 못 막아
처음부터 그랬어
You can't stop what's coming.
You never could.
You have...
넌
몰라
...no idea...
내 능력을...
...what I'm capable of.
Ah!
존
John.
불을 막네?
Fireproof?
곧 보여준댔잖아
I told you to stay tuned.
All right, give me that.
Come on.
그거 내놔
어서!
Thank you.
고맙다
Oh. Well, that was disappointing.
So, not a tracking device?
실망이네
추적기가 아니잖아
그래, 이젠 아니지
No, it was.
- 너도 느꼈어?
- 응
- Did you feel that, too?
- Yeah.
- We know where we need to go.
- Yeah, we can find the others.
어디로 갈지 알지?
응, 이젠
딴 애들을 찾을 수 있어
- Here.
- Thank you.
자
고마워
네가 곤란해지면
어쩌지?
I hope this doesn't get you in trouble.
Nah. Stuff goes missing from evidence
all the time.
걱정 마
증거물은 늘 잘 사라져
아빤 모르실 거야
My dad won't even know.
- You want to be heading west now.
- Why?
- 일단 서쪽으로 가
- 왜?
아빠한테
동쪽으로 간댔거든
Because I told my dad you're going east.
넘버 식스
샘도 같이 갈 거야
- Six, Sam's coming with us.
- What?
뭐?
안 돼
- No way.
- He's one of us now.
이제 한 팀이야
얘 아빠를 찾아야 돼
We need to find his father.
You slow us down,
I'll shoot you myself.
거치적대면 쏴버릴 거야
그래, 알아
그만 갈까?
And I believe you.
Could we go now?
내가 떠나야만 네가...
You know, I wouldn't leave
if it wasn't, uh...
- Safer.
- Yeah.
- 안전하다?
- 그래
알아
I know.
Really sorry about
what happened with Henri.
헨리 일은 정말 안됐어
나도 맘 아파
Me, too.
다시 널 찾아올게
You know I'll find you again.
Probably still be here.
난 아마 쭉 여기 있을 거야
중요한 건 장소가 아닌
사람이니까...
It's the people that make the place.
- Right?
- Yeah.
그래
헨리가 내 사랑은
단 한 번뿐이랬어
Henri warned me that
we only fall for one person.
Ever?
영원히?
영원히...
Ever.
파라다이스 오하이오
헨리 없이 떠나는 건
이곳이 처음이다
This is the first town
I've left without Henri.
다시 돌아올 곳도
이곳이 처음이다
But it's also the first one
I have a reason to come back to.
Henri was right,
we're stronger together.
헨리 말대로 우린
함께일 때 더 강하다
그래서 딴 애들을
찾아야한다
So we will find the others.
내 별의 이름은 로리언...
그러나 이젠 지구가 내 집이다
My planet is called Lorien,
but Earth is my home now.
It's as good a place
as any in the universe.
우주의 그 어디보다
아름다운 곳...
And that's how it's going to stay.
난 이곳을 지킬 것이다
아이 엠 넘버 포
(I Am Number Four, 2011)